VANESSA GIANNONI

Software Engineer

João Dajori, Cocal do Sul - Santa Catarina/Brazil +55 (48) 9.9932-1635 vanessa.o.giannoni@gmail.com Linkedin

ABOUT

I am a seasoned full-stack software engineer with over three years of hands-on experience in front-end development. I excel in communication, teamwork, and rapid adaptation to new technologies and projects. I enjoy sharing my technical expertise through blogging and creating a conducive environment for learning and collaboration. My current tech stack skills include NextJS, TypeScript, and several CSS libraries such as Bootstrap, Bulma, Chackra, Mantine, and Sass. Even with my focus on the front-end, I'm not leaving behind my studies in backend technologies; I'm currently learning Golang and have worked on projects with Python and PHP.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intermediate Software Engineer

ArcTouch - Full time SEP 2021 - MAY 2024

Intermediate Software Engineer - Trupanion - AUG 2023 - MAY 2024

The project involved three management platforms, a website for registering and selling pet life insurance, and a backend for the frontend (BFF). I worked in all areas, requiring flexibility, adaptation, and communication. I also helped colleagues and managers to ensure accessibility (AA), quality, and scalability.

Tech Skills: TypeScript; Next.js; Jest; Stripe; BFF; Accessibility; Leadership

Junior Software Engineer - ArcTouch - Zoho People - NOV 2022 - JUL 2023

I explored new technologies in this project and chose the most suitable one. The small API migration of Zoho People's HR system grew, requiring collaboration with the client to adapt a Python script for downloading and uploading data. I added tests with PyTest to improve the quality of the code.

Tech Skills: Python; PyTest; Google Sheets API; Leadership; Design;

Junior Software Engineer - HP - HP One - MAR 2022 - OCT 2023

At HP, I worked in two teams. In the first team, I created a micro-frontend orchestrator (MFE) to integrate new projects in various technologies with legacy ones, focusing on documentation and mapping. In the second one, I developed a platform for controlling HP One service plans using micro-frontends in ReactJS and TypeScript.

Tech Skills: React.js; TypeScript; Micro frontends; Jest;

Junior Software Engineer - McCormick - Bonecoin Super Bowl - NOV 2021 - JAN 2022

The project was intended to run during the Super Bowl in the USA and Canada. Users took photos of chicken wing bones and converted them into digital coins, which they could exchange for prizes. We developed a web app for mobile browsers and tablets.

Tech Skills: React.js; TypeScript; Sass;

Junior Software Engineer - GSK - The Think Tank Challenge - SEP 2021 - NOV 2022

The project was a static VUE website with a registration form. Target the Future" provides information about multiple myeloma and encourages patients to share their stories to boost scientific research into this rare cancer.

Tech Skills: VUE/Nuxt.js; Sass.

Software Engineer Jr.

L&M Sistemas - Full time JUN 2021 - AUG 2021

I worked on implementing the company's web development sector, as its initial focus was desktop development. To this end, I participated in developing a people management project for ABBA Pai Church where I could carry out everything from the navigation flow and UX/UI designs to creating the code using ReactJS.

Tech Skills: ReactJS; Bootstrap; Figma; Prototyping

Software Engineer

Ninsaúde - Intern

MAY 2020 - MAY 2021

I worked on maintaining and creating new features for Apolo, one of the company's main products, used by countless doctors and their teams in clinics in Brazil and other countries in South America; I carried out integrations, modeling, and making database and code changes.

Tech Skills: PHP; jQuery; Bootstrap; MySQL

Fullstack Developer

Góes & Nicoladelli Advogados Associados - Full time

NOV 2018 - OCT 2019

I worked on implementing new features for the company's intranet system using Laravel 5.2, PHP, jQuery, and MySQL and conducted user research and integration with APIs.

Tech Skills: PHP; MySQL; Laravel; jQuery

EDUCATION

SENAC

Analysis and Systems Development Degree

AUG/2022

ESCOLAS E FACULDADES QI

Technical Degree in Information Technology

OCT/2017

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Advanced English (B2)
- Spanish (native)
- Portuguese (native)

CERTIFICATES

- IAAP Certification Quick Guide
- Accessibility Fundamentals Disabilities, Guidelines, and Laws

VOLUNTARY WORK

• Development mentor at Technovation Girls Florianópolis (2024)